Russell Mstowski

Software Engineer

PROFILE

After thinking about majoring in Accounting throughout high school, I chose an AP Computer Science class as an elective during my senior year. This decision made me question what career choice would be best for me. Throughout my two years at the University of Illinois at Chicago, I never declared a major. Computer Science seemed more interesting to me, and I needed more time to figure things out for myself. During my two years at UIC, I enrolled in multiple CS classes and became familiar with Java, C, and C++, and my final decision was made about pursuing programming as a career. An opportunity to join the Actualize Coding Boot Camp and Apprenticeship program presented itself to me, and it has turned out to be an incredible experience. I am now familiar with multiple languages and frameworks and can pick up any new technology in a very short amount of time. I am currently looking for any full-time employment opportunities in the Chicagoland area and intend on pursuing a CS degree in the future.

PROJECTS

CarCustomizr

I created a fully functional web app called CarCustomizr. This app allows you to customize 3D models of cars. I built this app using Ruby on Rails for the backend and JavaScript/three.js for the front end. In order to customize a car, I used the three.js library to load a 3D model. With Blender, a 3D modeling software, i was able to change colors of the models and let users choose which color they'd like. I also built a native iOS app using React Native with the intention of letting users take pictures of a car and then with Augmented Reality, render and customize that model.

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Developer

The Difference Engine | Chicago, IL | February 2017 - present

• Working on a web app called trisomy families. The backend is built with Ruby on Rails and the frontend is built with Angular

Teaching Assistant

Actualize Coding Boot Camp | Chicago, IL | February 2017- present

• Assist students, troubleshoot their code, and develop programming skills

Full-Stack Web Developer-in-Training

Actualize Coding Boot Camp | Chicago, IL | October 2016 - January 2017

- 15-week full-stack web development training learning Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, AngularJS, SQL, postgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Worked in teams and learned to pair program
- Completed daily coding exercises
- Built a fully functional web and iOS app, CarCustomizr from scratch

Guest Advisor

Gamestop | Chicago, IL/USA | 2014 - 2016

- Greeted and helped guests
- Performed excellent customer service while troubleshooting computers/consoles/phones/tablets

SKILLS

Ruby

Rails

JavaScript

Angular

HTML CSS

D - - 4 - 4 - -

Bootstrap Git

SQL

PostgreSQL

C/C++

Java

Three.js

React Native

EDUCATION

Actualize Coding Boot Camp

Certificate of Web Development 2016-2017

University of Illinois-Chicago

2014 - 2016

Notable classes:

- cs111(program design I)
- cs141(program design II)

COMMUNITY

Orland Township Youth Commission

Volunteer | 2006 - 2012

CONTACT

Chicago, IL

russell.mstowski@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/russell-mstowski russell-mstowski.github.io